cooking.com 2012-06-09

# Cooking.com - Pledge

Our Pledge  
Use of Personal Information: What we collect & how we use it  
Information Shared with Third Parties  
Changing Your Information or Unsubscribing  
Links to/from Other Sites  
Cookies  
AOL Certified Merchant  
Notice of Changes

**Our pledge to you, our customer**  
Cooking.com respects your privacy. Our Internet site is meant to be a service to you. In order to provide you with the best products, timely information and quality customer service, we record a variety of information from your visit to our site. To better protect your privacy, we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

**Your personal information: what we collect and how we use it**

*  **When you enter personal information in to the Shopping Cart** , we collect your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address and credit card information. First, we use this information to fulfill your order and to communicate with you about your order. In fulfilling your order, we share your personal information with outside parties to the extent necessary to fulfill your order. In addition,

**a. Your First Use of the Shopping Cart at any Gourmet Catalog web-based store that is powered by Cooking.com** \- We use the information you provide to: 

  * **automatically place you on the store's e-mail list** to receive special offers and updates about products and services, unless you edit your subscription profile at the time your order is placed;
  * **automatically place you on the store's direct mail/catalog list** to receive from us direct mail and printed catalogs with special offers and updates about products and services; and
  * **make lists of our customers' names and postal addresses (but not e-mail addresses or phone numbers) available** to pre-screened companies who have specific direct mail (e.g. catalog) product or service offers that we think may be of interest to you.

**b. Your Subsequent Use of the Shopping Cart at Cooking.com** \- If you have purchased a product from a Cooking.com company before, unless you edit your subscription profile at the time your order is confirmed, your subscription status will remain unchanged.

Whether you are using the Shopping Cart for the first time or not, if you later decide that you want to be removed from a list or do not want us to share your name and postal address information, simply follow the instructions in the section "Reviewing, Changing Your Information or Unsubscribing" below.

*  **When you send a gift** and want it sent directly to the recipient, you will need to submit the recipient's name and postal address. We use this information only to ship the product and confirm delivery. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to fulfill that order. Information you provide us to create a gift-card is only used for that purpose, and it is only disclosed to the person receiving the gift.
*  **When you request a catalog from a Cooking.com company** we collect your name and postal address. We use this information to send you the catalog and then automatically place you on our direct mail/catalog list to receive from us direct mail and printed catalogs with special offers and updates about products and services. If you later decide that you do not wish to receive printed catalogs or other direct mail pieces, simply: (i) follow the instructions on the order form in the catalog; or (ii) follow the instructions in the section below "Reviewing, Changing Your Information or Unsubscribing." You also have the ability to sign up for our e-mail newsletters at the time you sign up for the direct mail/catalog list. To see what information we collect when you sign up for the e-mail newsletters, and how we use that information, see the section below "When you subscribe to our e-mail newsletters."
*  **When you request that we send a catalog to one of your friends** , we collect your friend’s name and postal address. We use this information to send the catalog to your friend. We add them to our direct mail/catalog list to send them direct mail and printed catalogs with special offers and updates regarding products and services. Your friend can unsubscribe at any time by: (i) following the instructions on the order form in the catalog; or (ii) following the instructions in the section below "Reviewing, Changing Your Information or Unsubscribing."
*  **When you subscribe to our e-mail newsletters** , we collect your e-mail address so that we can send you our e-mail newsletters with special offers and updates about products and services. You can unsubscribe from one or more of our e-mail newsletters at any time by (i) clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any electronic newsletter that you receive from us; or (ii) following the steps outlined below in the section "Reviewing, Changing Your Information or Unsubscribing." 
* **When you ask that we e-mail you when a product is back in stock** , we collect your name and e-mail address and use this information to e-mail you information on when the product is back in stock. Unless you uncheck the box at the time of making the request, we automatically place you on our e-mail newsletter list to receive Cooking.com Companies e-mail newsletters, special offers and/or new products and new services. You can unsubscribe from one or more of our e-mail newsletters at any time by (i) clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any electronic newsletter that you receive from us; or (ii) following the steps outlined below in the section "Reviewing, Changing Your Information or Unsubscribing."
*  **When you send us an e-mail to support@cooking.com** , we collect your name and e-mail address and use this to reply. We may also place you on our Cooking.com Companies e-mail newsletter list to receive our e-mail newsletters with special offers, new products and new services. You can unsubscribe from one or more of our e-mail newsletters at any time by (i) clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any electronic newsletter that you receive from us; or (ii) following the steps outlined below in the section "Reviewing, Changing Your Information or Unsubscribing."
*  **When you ask that we e-mail a recipe to one of your friends** , we collect your name and e-mail address, your friend’s name and e-mail address and the message you write. We use your friend’s name and e-mail address only to send them the link to the recipe and to send them your message. Unless you uncheck the box at the time of making your request, we use your name and e-mail address to place you on our e-mail newsletter lists to receive Cooking.com Companies e-mail newsletters with special offers, new products and new services. You can unsubscribe from one or more of our e-mail newsletters at any time by (i) clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any electronic newsletter that you receive from us; or (ii) following the steps outlined below in the section "Reviewing, Changing Your Information or Unsubscribing."
*  **When you enter a sweepstakes** sponsored by Cooking.com, we may ask for any or all of the following information: your name, postal address, e-mail address and telephone number. Check the official rules or the actual sweepstakes for what information is requested for any individual sweepstakes. Unless the official rules for a particular sweepstakes provide otherwise, when you provide your e-mail address you will be signed up for Cooking.com Companies e-mail newsletters and, if you provide us with your postal address, you will be added to our direct mail/catalog list. You can unsubscribe from the e-mail newsletters and/or direct mail/catalog list at any time by following the instructions in the section below "Reviewing, Changing Your Information or Unsubscribing."
*  **When you register at My Cooking.com** , we collect your name, address, telephone number and e-mail address. You can use My Cooking.com to update your account information, save addresses where you have sent products, track orders, create a personal wish list and save your favorite recipes. We also use the information you provide to:

  * **automatically place you on our e-mail lists** to receive special offers and updates about products and services; and
  * **automatically place you on our direct mail/ catalog list** to receive from us direct mail and printed catalogs with special offers and updates about products and services.
  * **automatically** send you emails to collect feedback related to your purchases.

If you want to be removed from a list, simply follow the instructions in the section "Reviewing, Changing Your Information or Unsubscribing" below.
*  **When you create a wedding registry at Cooking.com** , we collect your name, your spouse’s name, your shipping address, telephone number, wedding date (month and year) and location (city and state), email address, and if you provide them, your spouse’s email address and a customer password.

We use this information to maintain your wedding registry, help customers find it on our web site, and send you products purchased for you. We also use the information you provide to: 

  * Automatically place you on our e-mail newsletter lists to receive e-mails with special offers and updates about products and services; and
  * Automatically place you on our direct mail/catalog list to receive from us direct mail and printed catalogs with special offers and updates about products and services.

You can unsubscribe from the e-mail newsletters and/or direct mail/catalog list at any time by following the instructions in the section below “Reviewing, Changing Your Information or Unsubscribing.” When you ask that we notify your customers of your registry, we collect your customers’ name and e-mail address. We use your customers' name and e-mail address only to send them the notification e-mail.

When you create a registry, customers can see your names, wedding date (month and year), wedding location (city and state), the items you have registered for, and the quantities you have received. If you password-protect the customer view of your registry, customers initially see only your names, wedding date and location. They need a password (provided to them by you) to view the items you have registered for.

*  **If you are part of a rewards or incentive program** such as American Airline's AAdvantage Program that gives you "points" or other incentives for purchasing product on our website, we will share your information with the operator of the rewards or incentive program in order to enable them to credit you with the purchase.

**Information about customers and visitors shared with third parties**

* As described in the section "When you enter personal information into the Shopping Cart", in addition to being placed on our e-mail newsletter list and direct mail/catalog list, we may make your name and postal address available to pre-screened companies who have specific direct mail (e.g. catalog) product or service offers that we think may be of interest to you. If you do not want us to share your name and postal address information, simply follow the instructions in the section below "Reviewing, Changing Your Information or Unsubscribing."
* We also share information about our customers and visitors with trusted service providers who provide Cooking.com with specific services and/or administer activities offered on the Cooking.com site. (For example, we may provide customer information to companies that analyze our clickstream data in order to help us better design our site.)
* We also may use non-identifying and aggregate information (as opposed to identifiable individual information) about our customers and/or visitors to better design our website and we may provide it to advertisers and other third parties.

* We use DoubleClick and other third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please click here [Third Party Advertising](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp).

* Upon completing your purchase, we may present offers on behalf of third party partners on the order confirmation page. If you click on some of these promotional links and accept the offer(s), we will send your personal information to this party to complete the transaction. We do not share this information without your consent.

* We may share your personally identifiable information with participating sponsors to a program or promotion (e.g., a sweepstakes or contest) you enter via our web site. Further, we may share your personally identifiable information with third parties such as our co-marketing partners and others with whom we have marketing or other relationships. In some cases those participating sponsors and third parties may offer you products or services which may interest you. 

* On rare occasions, we may disclose specific information upon governmental request, in response to a court order, when required by law to do so, or protect the rights, property, or safety of Cooking.com, our users, or others. We may also share information with companies assisting in fraud protection or investigation. We do not provide information to these agencies or companies for marketing or commercial purposes.

**Reviewing, Changing Your Information or Unsubscribing**  
At any time you can unsubscribe, correct or update your information or modify your preferences pertaining to our newsletters, catalog and mailing list.

*  **To review, change or update information, as it pertains to our newsletters, you have several options:**

  * **On the Cooking.com Site**. Click on the "Help" button at the top of the home page then on the appropriate link under the "subscriptions" to change your information.
  * **By e-mail.** Send an email request to Customer Service.
  * **By postal mail.** Please include your email address and mail your request to us at 4086 Del Rey Avenue, Marina Del Rey, CA 90292: Attention: Customer Service.
  * **By phone.** Call toll-free at (800) 663-8810 in the USA and Canada.
  
(310) 450-3270 outside USA and Canada. 

* **To review, change or update information as it pertains to our catalog or the sharing of your name and postal address with third parties who offer a product or service we think may be of interest to you, you have several options:**

  * **On the Cooking.com Site**. Click on the "Help" button at the top of the home page then on the appropriate link under the “subscriptions" to change your information.
  * **By e-mail.** Send an email request to Customer Service.
  * **By postal mail.** Please follow these instructions and mail your request to us at 4086 Del Rey Avenue, Marina Del Rey, CA 90292: Attention: Customer Service.
  * **By phone.** Call toll-free at (800) 663-8810 in the USA and Canada.
  
(310) 450-3270 outside USA and Canada. 
To protect your privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access to this information or making corrections. Requests to be unsubscribed will be processed immediately, however you may receive additional newsletters for up to 1 week. Delays may occur if the email address or postal address information you provide us does not match the information in our database.

**Links to/from Other Sites**  
To enhance your shopping experience, the Cooking.com site may have links to other sites on the Internet that are owned by third party vendors and other third parties (External Sites), or you may come to Cooking.com from a link from an External Site. These other web sites will have their own rules on privacy that you should review. Cooking.com is not responsible for the privacy policies of External Sites.

**Cookies**  
Cooking.com uses a feature of your Internet Web browser called a cookie to assign an identification code to your computer. Cookies are files that your Web browser places on your computer’s hard drive. We do not and cannot use cookies to retrieve personal information about you from your computer unless such information was knowingly and willingly provided by you. Cookies do not provide us with access to any credit card information.

Third Party Cookies  
In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique "cookie" on your browser. 

**Our Commitment to Data Security**  
To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

**Cooking.com is an AOL Certified Merchant**  
As a Certified Merchant of America Online, we have agreed to abide by [AOL’s Privacy Policy](http://legal.web.aol.com/policy/aolpol/privpol.html). To read more about this policy, please visit AOL’s Privacy Policy. If you have further questions about Cooking.com’s privacy policy, please direct your inquiries to us via e-mail.

**Notice of Changes**  
Cooking.com’s Privacy Policy is subject to change without notice. At any time, you may visit our website to view the current policy.
